A Guide to the Josephine A. Dolan Collection of Nursing History 1995.0028
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series X: Extractions, 1851-1980 (Box 8)
  - Bellevue Bulletin 78(1), 1974.
  - Bellevue Training School for Nurses 1873-1923, Fiftieth Anniversary.
  - Blake, J. B., Public health in the town of Boston, 1630-1822. Cambridge: Harvard, (1959).
  - Bushel, A., Chronology of New York City Department of Health, 1955-1966
  - Catalog of the Florence Nightingale Collection. New York: Dept. of Nursing, Faculty of Medicine, Columbia University, Presbyterian Hospital, School of Nursing., (1956).
  - Ciba Pharmaceutical Products, Inc. Ciba Symposium, 4(7 and 8)., (1942).
  - Civil War Times, 1(2), 1962.
  - Cleary, F. (Ed.). Image: Sigma Theta Tau National Honor Society of Nursing, 4(1)., (1971).
  - Committee on the Structure of National Nursing Organizations. 1949 Handbook on the structure of organized nursing.
  - Connecticut Historical Society Bulletin, 39(3), 1974.
  - Crosby, A. B., The story of New England Hospital for Women and Children through seventy-five years, 1862-1937.
  - Deming, D., Penny Marsh public health nurse. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company., (1938).
  - Dolan, J. A., The grace of the great lady. Chicago: Medical Heritage Society., (1971).
  - Edith Cavell Nurse from Massachusetts. Boston: W. A. Butterfield., (1917).
  - Farmer, F. M. Food and cookery for the sick and convalescent. Boston: Little, Brown and Company., (1904).
  - Florence Nightingale Exhibit. National League for Nursing Convention. (1959).
  - Garrigan, M. A. L., Boston University Mugar Memorial Library History of Nursing Archive Report., (1970).
  - Geary, A. (Ed.)., The Crane .New York: Terry Printing., (1928)
  - Hallock, G. T. & Turner, C. E., Health Heroes: Florence Nightingale. New York: Metropolitan Life Ins. Co., (1928).
  - Harvard Medical Alumni Bulletin, 22(1), 1947.
  - Howard, M. W. Lowney's Cook Book (rev. ed.). Boston: Walter M. Lowney Co., (1912).
  - Hubbell, J. T. (Ed.). Civil War History, 18(3). Kent, OH: Kent State University Press., (1972).
  - Inside Health, 13(7), 1966.
  - International Council of Nurses. International Congress of Nurses Programme., (1947).
  - International Council of Nurses. Report for, 1951.
  - International Nursing Bulletin, 2(1), 1946.
  - International Nursing Bulletin, 2(2), 1946.
  - International Nursing Bulletin, 2(3), 1946.
  - International Nursing Bulletin, 2(4), 1946.
  - International Nursing Bulletin, 3(4), 1947.
  - Mackenzie, R., America and her army. London: T. Nelson and Sons, Paternoster Row; Edinburgh; and New York., (1865).
  - Miller, Mrs. J. Mother and Babe. New York: Mrs. J. Miller., (1884).
  - Morison, R. S. The knowledge explosion and its impact for health professions. New York: American Nurses' Association., (1964).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "Bell, book and candle: the National Commission and the school nurse." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "Continuing education in nursing: necessity and opportunity." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "The diploma nurse, the hospital school and the National Commission." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "Distributive nursing practice: development and fusion of the roles." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "Episodic nursing practice: refinement and expansion of the roles." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "Individualization, articulation, concentration: emergent forces in nursing education." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "The National Joint Practice Commission: new bottles, new wine." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "New patterns in nursing administration: the vanishing supervisor." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "No carrots, no sticks: motivation in nursing." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education. (Ed.). "Professional partnerhood in health care: the need for research into nursing practice." An abstract for action. New York: McGraw-Hill., (1970).
  - National Student Nurses' Association Convention Program. Dallas., (1971).
  - Newman, G. The commemoration of Florence Nightingale. Belgium: Office de Publicite., (1937).
  - Nightingale, F. Notes on nursing: what it is and what it is not. Philadelphia: Edward Stern & Company, Inc. (1946 facsimile of 1859 ed.).
  - Nightingale, F. The institution of Kaisersworth on the Rhine., (1959, 1851).
  - Nightingale Training School St. Thomas' Hospital, 1860-1960. London: Smith & Ebbs
  - Nightingale Training School St. Thomas' Hospital, 1860-1960. London., (1968).
  - Perkins, J. Westminster Abbey: The Nurses' Memorial Chapel. Skinner & Co.
  - Princess Mary's Gift Book. New York: Hodder & Stoughton., (undated).
  - Public Health Reports, 81(1), 1966.
  - Rhode-Island Almanack. Printed at Warren (R. I.) by Nathaniel Phillips, for Jacob Richardson, Esq.: Newport., (1794).
  - RN Magazine (Eds.). Florence Nightingale: rebel with a cause., (1970).
  - RN Magazine, 33(5), (1970).
  - Roberts, M. M. The Army Nurse Corps yesterday and today. United States Army Nurse Corps., (1955?).
  - Sloan, I. W. America's first trained nurse: the story of Linda Richards 1841-1930., (1941).
  - Southern Regional Assembly of Constituent Leagues for Nursing and the National League of Nursing Council of Public Health Nursing Services. Operation decision: citizen planning for nursing in the south. New York: National League of Nursing., (1968).
  - Sticker, A. Die Entstehung der neuzeitlichen krankenpflege. Stuttgart: Kohlhammer., (1960).
  - Sticker, A. Florence Nightingale curriculum vitae. Dusseldorf-Kaisersworth: Diakoniewerk., (1965).
  - Sticker, A. Theodor und Frederike Fliedner. Germany: Neukirchner Verlag des Erzeihungsvereins., (1965).
  - Stiles, H. R. The history of ancient Windsor, Connecticut. New York: Charles B. Norton., (1859).
  - Stowe, L. B. Saints, sinners and Beechers. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill., (1934).
  - Stowe-Day Foundation. Harriet Beecher Stowe's house in Nook Farm, Hartford. Stowe, Beecher, Hooker, Seymour, Day Foundation., (1970).
  - Sullivan, H. H. The Florence Nightingale Collection at Wayne State University. Detroit: Wayne State University Libraries., (1963).
  - Surgeon General's Consultant Group on Nursing. Toward quality in nursing: needs and goals. Public Health Service publication No. 992. Washington: United States Government Printing Office., (1963).
  - Tattershall, L. M. (1931). Census of Public Health Nursing in the United States, 1931. New York: National Organization for Public Health Nursing.
  - Tiffany, F. Life of Dorothea Lynde Dix. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin and Company. Cambridge: Riverside Press., (1891).
  - Waksman, S. A. The conquest of tuberculosis. Berkeley and Los Angeles: University of California Press., (1964).
  - Wellcome Museum of Medical Science. The Wellcome Museum of Medical Science, 1914-1964. Ipswich: W. S. Cowell Ltd.
  - Winslow, C.-E. A. The cost of sickness and the price of health. Geneva: World Health Organization., (1951).
  - Yale University School of Nursing Alumni Association. Engagement calendar., (1945).
  - Yale University School of Nursing. (1944). Alumni News.
- Series XI: 1998 Addition, 1940s-1980s
  - 1940s-1980 (Box 1998-0323_1)
    Scope and Contents
    Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, dummies, ephemera, notes, photographs, post cards, preliminary sketches, publications [Subjects include: American Nurses Association, Famous nurses, UConn School of Nursing.]
  - Awards, 1983; framed awards (Box 6)
    Scope and Content Note
    2 framed awards in the name of Jospehine A Dolan:
    -from the Boston University School of Nursing - Annual Alumni Award: Outstanding Alumna May 14, 1983 Signed by: Marcus C DePaul (President, Alumni) & Carmen B Westurik (Dean, School of Nursing) -"Doctorem Scientiae Nutriciae" from Boston College May 18, 1987 Signed by J Donald Monan, SJ (President of BC) The frame from "The Village Framers" Storrs, CT